RECRUITMENT TEAM

24.10.2019

Dear SIR | MADAM:

RE: COMMITTEE MEMBER - KEBS/TC 148/SC 01, KEBS

I am a Kenyan, experienced in ICT POLICY, REGULATIONS AND DIGITAL ECONOMY STRATEGY. I hold a **PhD** in **Information Systems**, with 13 years of relevant progressive work experience - five (5) years of which at managerial levels in Africa and Asia. I am experienced in policy and regulatory perspectives of digital transformation and general ICT4D.

I am at the moment serving as the **Policy and Advocacy Manager** within the **Mobile for Development Team** of **GSMA Foundation.** Through policy research, I manage the delivery of policy and advocacy programs with particular focus on **DIGITAL IDENTIFY AND MOBILE FOR HUMANITARIAN INNOVATION.** I also serve as a Member of Universal Service Advisory Council that advices on the strategic implementation of UNIVERSAL SERVICE FUND (USF) for digital inclusion.

I'd like to service in as a COMMITTEE MEMBER - KEBS/TC 148/SC 01, KEBS to contribute in the development of standard based solutions that promote innovation, trade and quality of life.

Sincerely,

@ ×

Kennedy Okong'o, PhD

+254 720 352 348

KENNEDY OKONGO

Ph.D.

(ICT Policy Specialist)

1. BIOGRAPHICAL DATA:

•TEL:+254 720 352 348 • EMAIL: KEN OKONGO@YAHOO.COM • CITIZENSHIP: KENYA •

2. BRIEF RESUME:

I have extensive knowledge of ICT policy and regulatory frameworks, having worked in Africa and Asia as a **public policy researcher, a business analyst and a project manager** in government, private sector and development agencies, with particular focus on **strategic digital transformation**. Through research and policy advocacy, I raise awareness of relevant actors regarding cross cutting issues in ICT4D. I am proficient in English and Kiswahili with a very basic French;

COMPETENCIES: Drafting, Presentation, Stakeholder Engagement, Policy Analysis and Reporting,

3. ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

Postgraduate: 2009-2016

Ph.D. in Information Systems, University of Cape Town, South Africa

MBA in Management Information Systems, University of Nairobi, Kenya

MA (Executive) in Diplomacy and Foreign Policy, Moi University, Kenya

MSc in ICT Policy and Regulation, JKUAT, Kenya

Undergraduate: 2001-2006

BSc in Geomatic Engineering and Geo-Information Systems, JKUAT, Kenya

4. EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

29.10.2018 TO PRESENT

Policy and Advocacy Manager

GSMA Mobile for Development Foundation Inc | Kenya

In a DFID strategic digital transformation partnership, I work with relevant actors across the globe in shaping policy and regulatory perspectives in **digital identity**, **rural connectivity**, **single digital market**, **e-governance**, **mobile for humanitarian innovation and data protection issues** through thought leadership and analytics to generate evidence and fill knowledge gaps;

11.09.2006 TO 01.10.2018

Positions Held:

ICT Policy Analyst; Market Research Analyst; Strategic Partnerships and Business Development Manager; Project Manager; Geospatial Market Analyst;

Projects | Engagements:

I have led and also been involved in a number of telecommunications projects as policy, regulation and infrastructure level. These include rural connectivity, e-governance, ICT4D / ICT4Education policy research, viability analysis of digital transformation programs / projects; strategic analysis of existing ICT4Education policies, regulations, legislations, technology & innovation (STI) guidelines, concept notes, frameworks, advisory and best practice notes;

5. BOARD / COUNCIL / ADVISORY POSITION

Member, Universal Service Advisory Council of the regulator, Kenya that offers advisory on regulatory frameworks for the design of universal service fund to drive digital inclusion for all.

6. PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Member, Computer Society of, Kenya (CSK); Member, Project Management Institute, USA (PMI-USA); Member, Institute of Directors, Kenya (IoD-K); Member, the Society for Conservation GIS, SCGIS-Kenya

7. SELECTED PUBLICATIONS, BOOKS & RESEARCH PAPERS:

Theodorou Y, Okong'o K and Yongo E (2019). Access to Mobile Services and Proof of Identity 2019: Assessing the Impact on Digital and Financial Inclusion. GSMA Mobile for Development, Barcelona – Spain. Okong'o K (2019). Mandatory SIM registration: Policy and Regulatory Perspectives in the absence of Data Protection Laws. GSMA Mobile for Development, London – United Kingdom.

Okong'o, K and Kyobe, M (2019). E-Governance as an Alternative Antecedent to a Lean Public Sector: Theory and Evidence. The African Journal of Information Systems: Vol. 11, Issue 1, Article 4.

Okong'o, K and Kyobe, M (2018). Empirical Examination of E-Government Information Systems in Developing Countries and Its Public Value in Kenya's Public Service. Electronic Journal of Information Systems Evaluation. ISSN: 1566-6379

Okong'o, K. (2018). <u>Systematic Refocus towards Digital Diplomacy.</u> Mauritius: LAP Lambert Academic Publishers. ISBN: 978-613-9-81650-7

Okong'o, K (2016). <u>Public Value of e-Government Information Systems in Developing Countries: Empirical Exploration of the Public Sector in Kenya. Unpublished PhD Thesis. Department of Information Systems, University of Cape Town.</u>

Okong'o, K (2015). Towards E-Diplomacy in Kenya: The Role of Communication Technologies in Public <u>Diplomacy.</u> Unpublished Master Thesis. Department of History, Political Science and Public Administration,

Moi University.

Okong'o, K (2015). Geographic Information System and the Implementation of Kenyan Vision 2030 in State

Department of Lands. Unpublished Master Thesis. School of Business, University of Nairobi.

Okong'o, K and Sakwa, M (2012). Evaluation of the Policy Implications of Bridging the Digital Divide in

Kenya. Exploration of Access-Involvement Interaction Model. Knowledge Management for Industrial

Innovation and Development. A Journal of the Management University of Africa Vol. 6, ISSN 2074-4730.

Okong'o, K (2012). <u>Bridging Digital Divide in Kenya using Access-Involvement-Interaction Policy Model.</u>

Empirical Exploration of Nairobi and its Environs. Unpublished Master Thesis. Jomo Kenyatta University of

Agriculture and Technology, Kenya.

Okong'o, K (2011). 3G Wireless Networks Driving Demand for 3D GIS Data. Kenya Engineer. Issue 26, March

/ April, 2011

Okong'o, K (2006). Spatial Information Systems for Strategic Service Expansion in Banking Sector: Case of

Barclays, Kenya. Unpublished Bachelor Dissertation. Department of Geospatial Information Systems,

JKUAT, Nairobi: Kenya

I hereby certify that the details, which I provided above, are all, to the best of my knowledge, true, complete

and accurate.

Date: 24.10.2019

Signature:

Kennedy OKONG'O, Ph.D.